CHUKWUJEKWU BENEDICT UMENZEKWE

verifiedceejay@gmail.com <u>My Portfolio</u> +2347036639585

LinkedIn-Profile

FRONTEND DEVELOPER SUMMARY

 Highly Skilled and Motivated FullStack Developer focused on FrontEnd Development with experience working with, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, ReactJs, NextJs, MongoDB, Express, Nodejs, and TailwindCSS. Strong problem-solving skills and a passion for optimizing software performance. Capable of integrating and working with various web APIs to enhance application functionality.

WORK EXPERIENCE

FrontEnd Developer CoverApp Digital Kyrenia, Cyprus

February 2020 - December 2023

- Developing innovative web and mobile applications
- · Maintenance and further development of existing applications
- · Design and development of database models
- Translating Figma Designs to a Fully Responsive Website
- · Optimization of existing functions in the frontend
- · Continuous improvement of processes depending on customer requirements

Web DesignerFirst World Connect Ltd Lagos, Nigeria

February 2017 - August 2019

- Planning, creation, and maintenance of websites, online portals, and internet presences.
- Development of the layout (colors, images, graphics, animations)
- HTML/CSS/JavaScript
- · Upload and manage files and website content.
- Website publishing, hosting, and domain management.
- Newsletter creation
- · Corporate Design
- · Help with marketing

IT Support Dangote Flour Mill Calabar, Nigeria

March 2015 - July 2016

- · Responding to customer inquiries and providing technical support via phone, email, or chat.
- · Troubleshooting and diagnosing technical issues, and providing solutions in a timely manner.
- Escalating more complex issues to 2nd or 3rd-level support.
- · Maintaining records of customer interactions and keeping track of technical issues and resolutions.
- · Collaborating with other team members to improve support processes and knowledge base articles.

EDUCATION

BSc Computer Science Tansian University Umunya

July 2010 - October 2014

SKILLS

MongoDB	HTML/CSS	Javascript
ReactJs	Tailwind CSS	NextJS

NodeJS Express